Guide to the Blukis Onat Applied Sciences (BOAS), Inc. Papers 1968-2010
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- 45SK225, Swinomish Channel Marina, Assessment of Buried Cultural Resources and Testing Skagit County: report., 1997 March (Box-folder 32/6, Project 199602.5t)
- RESTRICTED -- Vancouver Lakes Archaeological District and the Vancouver Lowlands Mitigation Wildlife Area, Cultural Resources Site Survey for Washington Department of Fish and Wildlife, Clark County: original report and bound copy., 1997 April (Box-folder 62R/4-5, Project 199604)
- RESTRICTED -- Vancouver Lakes Archaeological District and the Vancouver Lowlands Mitigation Wildlife Area, Cultural Resources Site Survey for Washington Department of Fish and Wildlife, Clark County: 3.5 inch data disk; correspondence; 1982 determination of eligibility to National Register of Historic Places documents for Vancouver Lakes Archaeological District and related correspondence (1982-1983, 1985); photocopies of historical documents and maps (1888, 1892, 1943, 1948) and site forms., 1888, 1892, 1943, 1948, 1982-1983, 1985, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 63R/1, Project 199604)
- RESTRICTED -- Vancouver Lakes Archaeological District and the Vancouver Lowlands Mitigation Wildlife Area, Cultural Resources Site Survey for Washington Department of Fish and Wildlife, Clark County: topographic maps with site locations marked., 1996 (Box-folder 77R/3, Project 199604)
- Surface Water Management Division in Department of Public Works, Archaeological and Cultural Resources Project Reviews, King County: color prints and negatives; photographic log; field notes; and 56 letter reports on various projects. (Box-folder 32/7, Project 199605)
- RESTRICTED -- Camp Creek Rockshelter (45LE263), Archaeological Testing and Mapping Project (3 phases) for Gifford Pinchot National Forest, Lewis County: color prints; field notes; field artifact catalog sheets; site map; stratigraphic profiles; and reports (3)., 1996 (Box-folder 63R/2, Project 199606.1, 199606.2, 199606.3)
- RESTRICTED -- Janine's Lakeside Site (35CL196 or #662NA92) and Summit Lake Planning Area, Cultural Resource Inventory of Timber Management Units, Gifford Pinchot National Forest, Clackamas County, Oregon: correspondence; US Forest Service Cultural Resource Site Report (662NA92, 662EA47) and Determination of Effect forms; maps; and report., 1984, 1988, 1989, 1991, 1996 (Box-folder 63R/3, Project 199607)
- RESTRICTED -- 6 Archaeological Sites (42SA364 to 369 and 45SA375) and Skis-wa-tum (Surprise Lakes) Campground Road Repair Project, Cultural Resource Inventory, Gifford Pinchot National Forest, Skamania County: correspondence; topographic map with site locations; and original and bound report., 1998 (Box-folder 63R/4-5, Project 199608)
- Frostad Road Project, Cultural Resources Assessment for Reid Middleton, Inc., Island County: 5-page letter report., 1996 December 11 (Box-folder 32/8, Project 199609)
- Proposed Marblemount Community Park Facility including 45SK139, Pressentin County Park, Cultural Resource Survey for Skagit County Parks and Recreation, Skagit County: color prints and negatives; correspondence; project maps; research materials; original and bound report., 1995-1997 (Box-folder 32/9-10, Project 199610.1, 199610.2)
- Proposed Reservation Road Improvement Project CRO #4021-1, Cultural Resource Assessment, Skagit County: report., 1997 January (Box-folder 33/1, Project 199611)
- Swadabs Intertidal Habitat Restoration Project, Core Probing Survey of Buried Cultural Resources especially 45SK31,Skagit County: report., 1997 May (Box-folder 33/2, Project 199702.1)
- Lois Fornsby Homesite, Cultural Resource Assessment, Skagit County: correspondence., 1997 March 24 (Box-folder 33/3, Project 199702.2)
- Partridge Point Burial Recovery and Site Review (45IS218), Island County: correspondence and archaeological site inventory form., 1997 (Box-folder 33/4, Project 199702.3)
- East Camano Drive Road Improvements, Cultural Resource Assessment, Island County: field notes and 3-page letter report., 1997 (Box-folder 33/5, Project 199704)
- RESTRICTED -- Construction associated with Tolt Filtration Facility, Artifact Awareness and Outline for Data Recovery Plan under CDM Philip (Philip Services) for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: correspondence regarding plan and plan document with project maps., 1997-1998 (Box-folder 64R/1-2, Project 199705.1 (see also 198707 and 199013))
- RESTRICTED -- 45KI464 (Stuwe'yuqw) and Tolt Filtration Facility, Site Discovery, Proposal for Data Recovery Excavation, and Data Recovery Excavations (Phase 2 and 2b) under CDM Philip (Philip Services) for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: correspondence; archaeological excavation permit; field crew recruitment with resumes; field lab procedures - Paragon Research Associates (1998); weekly excavation reports including rapid excavation activity Phase 2b (August-November 1998) with photographs; data recovery excavation draft, comments, and final proposal., 1998 (Box-folder 64R/3-7, Project 199705.2)
- RESTRICTED -- 45KI464 (Stuwe'yuqw) and Tolt Filtration Facility, Volunteer Phase at Request of Snoqualmie Tribe under Grant to Advocates for Archaeology and Historic Preservation (non-profit) from King County Landmarks and Heritage Commission for 1999 Volunteer Excavations and 1999-2000 Curriculum Development for Snoqualmie and Chief Kanim Middle Schools: amended archaeological excavation permit; correspondence; grant application; grant contracts; miscellaneous materials; and final report., 1998-2000 (Box-folder 64R/8, Project 199705.2a)
- RESTRICTED -- 45KI464 (Stuwe'yuqw) and 45KI489 and Tolt Filtration Facility, Data Recovery and Phase 3 Laboratory Analysis and Report Writing for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: 3 3.5 inch floppy disks and 2 CDs with report, forms, and figures; amended archaeological excavation permit; correspondence 1999-2000 regarding 45KI464 and 45KI489; consultant correspondence and specialized reports such as lithic analysis and sourcing, pollen, soil, stratigraphy with CD; laboratory procedures log; report illustrations; Phase 3 proposal for analysis and report preparation with proposal review and response; 45KI464 site form - 2000 update; 2-volume report with 3 volumes of appendices., Dec. 1998-2001 (Box-folder 65R/1-8, Project 199705.3)
- RESTRICTED -- 45KI464 (Stuwe'yuqw) and 45KI489 and Tolt Filtration Facility, Data Recovery and Phase 3 Laboratory Analysis and Report Writing for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: report appendices., 2001 (Box-folder 66R/1-2, Project 199705.3)
- RESTRICTED -- 45KI464 (Stuwe'yuqw) and 45KI489 and Tolt Filtration Facility, Cultural Resource Recovery for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: newspaper articles about Tolt project; Archaeology Month brochures with activities at stuwe'yuqw (1998, 1999); miscellaneous articles; Seattle Public Utilities Tolt Facility materials including CD; professional conference materials on 45KI464 frm 1999 Northwest Anthropological Conference and 2000 Society for American Archaeology.; and other items., 1998-2002 (Box-folder 66R/3-4, Project 199705)
- 45KI464 (Stuwe'yuqw) and Tolt Filtration Facility, Cultural Resource Recovery for Seattle Public Utilities (Water Department), King County: Standard VHS videotape created by City of Seattle for "Seattle Focus" on the city's Governmental Access Channel (called TVSea in 2001 and Seattle Channel in 2014) about the Tolt Facility and stuwe'yuqw, 11:41 length., 2001 (Box-folder 79/20, Project 199705)
- Tollgate Farm (45KI455h) and Prehistoric Site (45KI454), Archaeological and Historic Resource Assessment of Proposed Tollgate Farm Development with Response to Public Comments, King County: correspondence and reports., 1997, 1999, 2002 (Box-folder 33/6, Project 199707.1, 199707.2)
- Snohomish County Public Works Projects, Cultural Resource Assessments for assorted road improvement and curb work including 196th Street SW and 132nd Street SE, bike paths,and State Route 92 relocation near Granite Falls, Snohomish County: correspondence, project maps, and reports., 1997-1999 (Box-folder 33/7-11, Project 199708.1 through 199708.5)
  This material may not be copied without permission, please contact MASC for details: 199708.2 and 199708.5 Open and available for research use: 199708.1, 199708.3 and 199708.4
- Sagebrush Flat Wildlife Area, Cultural Resource Assessment for Washington State Department of Fish and Wildlife, Douglas County: field notes; project maps: photographic log; original and bound report., 1998-1999 (Box-folder 33/12, Project 199709)
- Swanson Lakes Wildlife Area (SLWA), Lincoln County: 5 USGS 7.5' topographic maps with duplicate for each and without annotations indicating site locations., 1969 (Box-folder 80 o.s./1-10, Project 199710)
- RESTRICTED - Swanson Lakes Wildlife Area (SLWA), Cultural and Historical Resource Survey for Washington Department of Fish And Wildlife, Lincoln County: correspondence; National Register of Historic Places Multiple Property forms; local informant interview transcripts; historic site forms; and project maps., n.d., 1980, 1987, 1995, 1997-1998, 2000 (Box-folder 66R/5-8, Project 199710)
- RESTRICTED - Swanson Lakes Wildlife Area (SLWA), Cultural and Historical Resource Survey for Washington Department of Fish And Wildlife, Lincoln County: aerial photographs; color prints, negatives, and slides; correspondence; field notes; prehistoric and historic site forms; photographic logs; and project maps., 1992, 1997-1998, 2000 (Box-folder 67R/1-14, Project 199710)
- RESTRICTED - Swanson Lakes Wildlife Area (SLWA), Cultural and Historical Resource Survey for Washington Department of Fish And Wildlife, Lincoln County: color prints, negatives, and slides; 3 data CDs and 1 3.5 inch floppy disk presumably with report and figures; original and bound report., 1998, 2000, 2001 (Box-folder 68R/1-8, Project 199710)
- Proposed Penn Cove Park Water District Water System Improvements and Sites 45IS49 and 45IS50, Archaeological Survey, Evaluation, and Monitoring of Sites, Whidbey Island, Island County: excavation permit and reports., 1997 and 2004 (Box-folder 33/13-14, Project 199711 and 199711a)
- Meadowbrook Farm Project and Prehistoric Site 45KI458, Archaeological and Historic Resource Assessment, King County: correspondence and report., 1998, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 33/15, Project 199712)
- Traditional Cultural Properties Administrative Memorandum of Agreement, Seattle City Light with Sauk-Suiattle Tribe, Upper Skagit Tribe, and Swinomish Indian Tribal Community: correspondence; draft and signed agreement., 1995-1996 (Box-folder 34/1, Project 199713)
- Sunnyside Wildlife Area, Cultural Resources Site Survey, Benton and Yakima Counties: 1 data CD and 2 3.5 inch floppy disks presumably with report, forms, and figures; original and bound report (1 of 2)., 1998 (Box-folder 34/2, Project 199714.1)
- Sunnyside Wildlife Area, Cultural Resources Site Survey, Benton and Yakima Counties: bound site records volume (2 of 2)., 1998 (Box-folder 34/3, Project 199714.2)
- Sunnyside Wildlife Area, Cultural Resources Site Survey, Benton and Yakima Counties: original of site records volume (2 of 2)., 1998 (Box-folder 34/4, Project 199714.2)
- Proposed Improvement to I-90 Across Mercer Island, Cultural Resources Assessment for Washington Department of Transportation, King County: report., 1999 (Box-folder 35/1, Project 199801)
- New Medical Building and Site 45SK31, Cultural Resource Testing, Swinomish Reservation, Skagit County: correspondence and letter report., 1998 (Box-folder 35/2, Project 199802.1)
- Snee-oosh Road Private Property Improvement and Site 45SK19, Testing and Mitigation of Effects to Cultural Resources, Skagit County: letter report., 1998 (Box-folder 35/3, Project 199802.2)
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement, Recommendations for Monitoring and Mitigation of Effects to Cultural Resources, Island County: correspondence., 1999 (Box-folder 35/4, Project 199802.3)
- RESTRICTED - Gibralter Burial Site (45SK217), Site Discovery and Gibralter Land Development Company Forest Practice Application, Skagit County: correspondence and site form., 1991, 1992, 1999 (Box-folder 68R/9, Project 199802.4)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement and Site 45IS28, Assessment of Effect on Archaeological Resources, Island County: letter report., 1998 March 11 (Box-folder 35/5, Project 199803)
- Fort Dent Park Reclaimed Water Improvement Project, Archaeological Monitoring of Effect to Cultural Resources, King County: color negatives and prints; correspondence; field notes; and letter report., 1998 (Box-folder 35/6, Project 199805)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement, Cultural Resources Review, Island County: letter report., 1998 April 22 (Box-folder 35/7, Project 199806)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement and Site 45IS28, Archaeological Assessment of Impact to Site, Island County: letter report., 1998 May 15 (Box-folder 35/8, Project 199807)
- Reservation Road Improvements, Cultural Resources Assessment, Skagit County: letter report., 1998 June 14 (Box-folder 35/9, Project 199808)
- RESTRICTED - Griffin Creek Site 45KI55 and Lower Griffin Creek Site [45KI497], Cultural Resource Studies and Comparisons to 45KI464, Field Work by BOAS and Analysis by HSW Enterprises, King County: correspondence; lithic analysis notes; project map; site form; and report., 1998-2000, 2002 (Box-folder 68R/10, Project 199809)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement and Site 45IS17, Archaeological Assessment of Impact to the Site, Island County: color negatives and prints; correspondence; field notes; photo log; site form; and letter report., 1998 (Box-folder 35/10, Project 199810)
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement and Site 45IS84, Archaeological Assessment of Impact to the Site, Island County: letter report., 1998 July 23 (Box-folder 35/11, Project 199811)
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement and Site 45IS9, Archaeological Assessment of Impact to the Site, Island County: color prints; correspondence; field notes; and letter report., 1998 (Box-folder 35/12, Project 199812)
- Whidbey Island Bayview Road Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Survey, Island County: 1 data CD (Mac) labeled "Bayview Map"; color negatives and prints; field notes; and letter report, copy and original., 1999 (Box-folder 35/13, Project 199901)
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Survey, Island County: 1 data CD and 2 3.5 inch floppy disks presumably with report, forms, and figures; color negatives and prints; field notes; and letter report., 1999 (Box-folder 35/14, Project 199902)
- Camano Island Cama Beach and 45IS2, Review of Prior Cultural Resource Work and Assessment of Need for Additional Investigations in Relation to State Parks Development Plans for Swinomish Indian Tribal Community: letter report., 1999 October 20 (Box-folder 35/15, Project 199903.1)
- South Hill Park and Ride, Puyallup, Cultural Resource Assessment for Washington State Department of Transportation, Pierce County: correspondence and letter report., 1999 (Box-folder 35/16, Project 199905)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS28, Cultural Resource Assessment, Island County: letter report., 1999 April 30 (Box-folder 35/17, Project 199906)
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS8, Archaeological Assessment of Impact to the Site, Island County: color negatives and prints; correspondence; field notes; and letter report., 1999 (Box-folder 35/18, Project 199907)
- Surface Water Management Division in Department of Public Works, Archaeological and Cultural Resources Project Reviews, King County: 8 letter reports on various projects., 1998-1999 (Box-folder 35/19, Project 199908 (see also 199605))
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Survey, Island County: color negatives and prints; correspondence; field notes; photo log; and letter report., 1999, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 35/20, Project 199909 200308)
- Camano Island Private Property and Sites 45IS7 and 45IS8, Preliminary Archaeological Evaluation of Prehistoric and Historic Resources, Island County: color negatives and prints; correspondence; field notes; historic resources research; and letter report., 1999 (Box-folder 35/21, Project 199912)
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Survey, Island County: correspondence and letter report., 1999-2000 (Box-folder 36/1, Project 199913)
- Sewer Line on Whidbey Island and Site 45IS54, Cultural Resources Survey, Island County: letter report., 1999 (Box-folder 36/2, Project 199914)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS13, Cultural Resource Assessment, Island County: correspondence and letter report., 1999-2000 (Box-folder 36/3, Project 199915)
- Manuscript "Two Voices, A History of the Sauk and Suiattle People and Sauk Country Experiences," Jean Bedal Fish and Edith Bedal, with editorial assistance by A.R. Blukis Onat., 2000 (Box-folder 36/4, Project 200003)
- South Lake Stevens Road Walkway, Archaeological Survey for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: field notes; project map; and letter report., 2000 (Box-folder 36/5, Project 200004.01)
- Proposed Snohomish County Central Recycling and Transfer Station (CRTS) Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; field notes; project aerial photo and maps; photo log; and original and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 36/6, Project 200004.02)
- Proposed Silverton Bridge No. 56 Replacement Project, Silverton, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; field notes; maps; photo log; and original and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 36/7, Project 200004.03)
- Proposed Interurban Trail Overcrossings and Road Modifications Projects, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; field notes; maps; and original and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 36/8, Project 200004.04)
- Proposed Swanson Bridge No. 80 Replacement Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; field notes; project maps; and original and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 36/9, Project 200004.05)
- Sites 45SN19 and 45SN300 and Proposed South Machias Road/OK Mill Road Modifications and Machias Bridge No. 44 & Dubuque Creek Bridge No. 423 Replacement Projects, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: 1 3.5 inch floppy disk presumably with report, forms, and figures; color negatives and prints; field notes; photo log; project maps; site forms; and original and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 36/10, Project 200004.06)
- Proposed Woods Creek Bridge No. 445 Replacement Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color prints; field notes; and original (2001 and 2005) and bound report (2005)., 2001, 2005 (Box-folder 36/11, Project 200004.07 and 200306.19)
- Proposed Larch Way - Poplar Way Intersection Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; field notes; photo log; and original and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 37/1, Project 200004.08)
- Proposed 148th Street Southwest Road Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; field notes; photo log; and original and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 37/2, Project 200004.09)
- Proposed Lundeen Parkway Extension Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; draft Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement (1994); and original and bound report., 1994, 2001 (Box-folder 37/3, Project 200004.10)
- BOAS-coordinated Historic Preservation Workshop (Section 106) for Snohomish County Staff: correspondence and materials., 2000-2001 (Box-folder 37/4, Project 200004.11)
- Proposed Little Pilchuck Bridge No. 268 Replacement Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; field notes; and original and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 37/5, Project 200004.12)
- Proposed Woods Creek Bridge No. 6 Replacement Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color negatives and prints; correspondence (1996); field notes; project map; and original and bound report., 1996, 2001 (Box-folder 37/6, Project 200004.15 (see also 199405.3))
- Review of Previous Projects (199205.2 and 199405.1), Permitting Assistance for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: correspondence and copy of 199205.2 report., 1994, 2002 (Box-folder 37/7, Project 200004.16 (see also 199405.1 and 199205.2))
- Sauk River Bridge # 414 Replacement, Cultural Resource Inventory for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: photo CD; color negatives and prints; correspondence; field notes; and original and bound report., 2003 (Box-folder 37/8, Project 200004.18)
- 196th Street SW (SR-524) from 24th Avenue W to SR-527 Road Improvement Projects, Cultural Resources Assessment for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: correspondence; color prints and negatives; photo log; project map; letter report and original and bound final report., 2002-2003 (Box-folder 37/9, Project 200004.17 200004.19 (see also 198804.1 and 199708.4))
- Map and Aerial Photo Resources Used for Various Phases of Central Link Light Rail Project, King County: aerial photo with site locations; photocopies of many historic maps of Seattle vicinity including 1862-63 and 1897 GLO maps also of Seattle, 1907 Duwamish-Puyallup survey, and 1912 "Kroll's Atlas of Seattle"; 1980 hydrology report., 1862-1863, 1897, 1907, 1912, 1980 (Box-folder 73/10, Project 200005)
- Geoarchaeological Assessment for Paleontological and Prehistoric Archaeological Resources as part of BOAS Archaeological Resources Monitoring and Treatment Plan (ARMT) for Central Link Light Rail Project (CLLR), King County: report., 2003 July (Box-folder 38/1, Project 200005.A1)
- Historical Archaeological Assessment as part of BOAS Archaeological Resources Monitoring and Treatment Plan (ARMT) for Central Link Light Rail Project (CLLR), King County: correspondence; radiocarbon dates; 35 mm color slides; and report., 2003 (Box-folder 38/2, Project 200005.A2)
- Duwamish River Bend Site 45KI703, Archaeological Data Recovery Plan and Results for CLLR Project, King County: data and photo CDs: correspondence; analyses (such as radiocarbon dating) results; data recovery plan; and data recovery report., 2004-2006, 2009, 2010 (Box-folder 38/3-4, Project 200005.A3a and 20005.A3b3)
- Tukwila (including 45KI703) and Poverty Hill, Cultural Resources Recovery for CLLR Project, King County: photo CD; color negatives; and report., 2000, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 38/5, Project 200005.A3b1 and 200005.A3b2)
- BOAS Archaeological Resources Monitoring and Treatment (ARMT) Plans for Maintenance Base and Initial Segment of Central Link Light Rail Project (CLLR), King County: correspondence and reports., 2002, 2004 (Box-folder 38/6, Project 200005.B (B1 and B2))